<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: dd-wrt | draptik]]></title>
  <link href="http://draptik.github.io/blog/categories/dd-wrt/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://draptik.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2018-11-29T01:21:37+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://draptik.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Patrick Drechsler]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pi Hole - simple ad blocker for your network]]></title>
    <link href="http://draptik.github.io/blog/2017/01/10/pi-hole-simple-ad-blocker-for-your-network/"/>
    <updated>2017-01-10T23:01:24+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://draptik.github.io/blog/2017/01/10/pi-hole-simple-ad-blocker-for-your-network</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Advertisements in web pages can be a nuisance. But they are a necessary evil because companies/bloggers producing high quality content have to earn a living. <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Troy_Hunt">Troy Hunt</a> recently wrote a <a href="https://www.troyhunt.com/ad-blockers-are-part-of-the-problem/">nice post on the subject</a>.</p>

<p>Most <strong>desktop browsers</strong> provide &ldquo;ad blockers&rdquo; as plugins. These plugins normally also have configurable whitelists (whitelist: a list of sites exluded from being blocked) &#8212; which you should use for those sites which (a) provide high quality content and (b) rely on advertisements for a living.</p>

<p>Other devices in our home network also communicate with the web:</p>

<ul>
<li>cell/smart phones (f.ex. iPhone, Android)</li>
<li>smart TVs (f.ex. <a href="https://www.cnet.com/news/samsungs-warning-our-smart-tvs-record-your-living-room-chatter/">Samsung</a>)</li>
<li>and all those new IoT devices (IoT: Internet of Things): those &ldquo;smart&rdquo; home automation devices that communicate with &ldquo;the cloud&rdquo; and your &ldquo;smart phone&rdquo;</li>
</ul>


<p>We can&rsquo;t install &ldquo;ad blockers&rdquo; on these devices.</p>

<p>Here is where <a href="https://github.com/pi-hole/pi-hole">Pi Hole</a> comes into play: We can plug a Raspberry Pi straight into our router!</p>

<p>My experience:</p>

<p>On my phone (an old Galaxy-S4) web pages load a <strong>hell of a lot faster</strong> when I&rsquo;m in my home network compared to outside of my home network.</p>

<p>The Pi Hole web interface looks like this:</p>

<p><img src="/images/posts/pi-hole/screenshot-pi-hole-25-percent-blocked-requests.png"></p>

<p>As you can see in the screenshot: ~20% traffic is blocked (!) and you can configure whitelists just like with those browser plugins. <strong>Nobody in my household noticed that 20% traffic was blocked</strong>.</p>

<p>Installing the software on your Raspberry Pi is straightforward: Just follow the instructions on the <a href="https://github.com/pi-hole/pi-hole">Pi Hole</a> website.</p>

<p>Configuring your router is another beast: OpenWRT and DD-WRT router instructions are available (<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=TzFLJqUeirA">example &ndash; short youtube promo</a>).</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
